So as anyone can use free bands if we want, we can build our own private network.
This means that we can position our own gateways, integrate our own network server and application
server, and we can even build our own Iot platform.
It's called a "Private Network".
Obviously, if you want to set that up, then you need a very good knowledge about the technology to
configure the gateway to install an administrator servers, and it also costs quite a lot of money at
the beginning because you need to buy expensive hardware for gateways.
The price of the gateway varies a lot depending on the type and the features.
But let's say that's for a good outdoor gateway.
It's around 800 € plus the installation fees and the installation can be quite expensive.
If you want to install them on rooftops.
On the other hand, we not have to pay for a subscription to use the network and we are not subject
to any restriction that an operator can apply, like a limit on the number of uplink or a limit on the
number of downlink frames.
Later in this course, we'll install a private network.
So obviously with our own gateway and we'll also install two different LoRa network server stacks called
ChirpStack first.
Then there will be another one called The Things stack.
These two stacks are free and open source, but we could also have chosen a proprietary network server
like Actility, for example.
They are all compliant with the LoRaWAN specification, but the pricing depends on the level of service
and the level of support that you need to set up your network.